<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ouR data generation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ouR data generation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>keith.goldfeld@nyumc.org (Keith Goldfeld)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>keith.goldfeld@nyumc.org (Keith Goldfeld)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It can be easy to explore data generating mechanisms with the simstudy package</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-simstudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keith.goldfeld@nyumc.org (Keith Goldfeld)</author>
      <guid>/post/intro-to-simstudy/</guid>
      <description>I learned statistics and probability by simulating data. Sure, I did the occasional proof, but I never believed the results until I saw it in a simulation. I guess I have it backwards, but I that’s just the way I am. And now that I am a so-called professional, I continue to use simulation to understand models, to do sample size estimates and power calculations, and of course to teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone knows that loops in R are to be avoided, but vectorization is not always possible</title>
      <link>/post/first-blog-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keith.goldfeld@nyumc.org (Keith Goldfeld)</author>
      <guid>/post/first-blog-entry/</guid>
      <description>It goes without saying that there are always many ways to solve a problem in R, but clearly some ways are better (for example, faster) than others. Recently, I found myself in a situation where I could not find a way to avoid using a loop, and I was immediately concerned, knowding that I would want this code to be flexible enough to run with a very large number of observations, possibly over many observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>keith.goldfeld@nyumc.org (Keith Goldfeld)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Keith Goldfeld and I am on the faculty in the Division of Biostatistics, which is part of the Department of Population Health at the NYU School of Medicine, located in New York City.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>